[
  {
    "Question": "What is the earliest surviving system of laws?",
    "Answer": "The Code of Hammurabi",
    "A": "Rosetta stone",
    "B": "Shabaka stone",
    "C": "The Code of Hammurabi",
    "D": "Hebrew torah",
    "Description": "The Code of Hammurabi is the earliest known example of a ruler publicly proclaiming to his people an entire set of laws, in an orderly arrangement, so that all men might read and know what was required of them. Hammurabi was a ruler of ancient Babylon, probably from around 1795 B.C. to about 1750 B.C. His code was carved on a black stone monument, in 3,600 lines of cuneiform, standing eight feet high, and obviously intended for public view."
  },
  {
    "Question": "What was the last battle of the Napoleonic Wars?",
    "Answer": "The Battle of Wavre",
    "A": "Battle of Trafalgar",
    "B": "Battle of Waterloo",
    "C": "Battle of the Nile",
    "D": "The Battle of Wavre",
    "Description": "The Battle of Wavre was the last battle of the Napoleonic Wars. It took place on June 18 and 19, 1815, between Prussian and French forces. Although the Prussians, outnumbered nearly two to one, were driven back, the Battle of Wavre prevented several French corps from participating in the Battle of Waterloo on June 18, 1815, thus contributing to the final downfall of Napoleon. Although deposed following this battle, Napoleon remained at large for a time in France. Eventually, he was exiled to Saint Helena where he died in 1821."
  },
  {
    "Question": "Who was the first democratically elected President of Russia?",
    "Answer": "Boris Yeltsin",
    "A": "Mikhail Gorbachev",
    "B": "Vladimir Putin",
    "C": "Boris Yeltsin",
    "D": "Nikita Krushchev",
    "Description": "In 1991, Boris Yeltsin became the first democratically elected President of Russia. As President, Yeltsin supported private property, a free press, stronger human rights, and an end to state control of the economy. He announced his resignation on December 31, 1999, due to health concerns and political pressures."
  },
  {
    "Question": "What is the correct chronological order, from earliest to latest, of the development of the following religions?",
    "Answer": "Buddhism, Christianity, Islam",
    "A": "Buddhism, Christianity, Islam",
    "B": "Islam, Christianity, Buddhism",
    "C": "Christianity, Islam, Buddhism",
    "D": "Islam, Buddhism, Christianity",
    "Description": "Buddhism developed in the sixth century B.C., Christianity in the first and second centuries A.D., and Islam in the seventh century A.D."
  },
  {
    "Question": "Which of the following inventions was the first to be patented?",
    "Answer": "Rubber band",
    "A": "Dishwasher",
    "B": "Chewing gum",
    "C": "Cash register",
    "D": "Rubber band",
    "Description": "In 1845, Stephen Perry, of the rubber manufacturing company Messers Perry and Co., invented the rubber band to hold papers or envelopes together. On March 17, 1845, Perry patented the rubber band. These first rubber bands were made of vulcanized rubber. The first dishwasher was patented by Joel Houghton in 1850. The first chewing gum was patented by William Finley Semple in 1869. The first cash register was patented by James Ritty in 1879."
  },
  {
    "Question": "What was the first city to reach a population of one million?",
    "Answer": "Rome",
    "A": "London",
    "B": "Rome",
    "C": "New York",
    "D": "Beijing",
    "Description": "Ancient Rome became the first city to reach a population of one million in 5 B.C. It would be more than eighteen centuries before the second such city, London, would reach that milestone in 1800."
  },
  {
    "Question": "How long did the Hundred Years' War last?",
    "Answer": "116 years",
    "A": "100 years",
    "B": "99 years",
    "C": "116 years",
    "D": "110 years",
    "Description": "The Hundred Years' War, a conflict between England and France, actually lasted 116 years. It began in 1337 and ended in 1453, although there were long periods of truce or low-level fighting during that time."
  },
  {
    "Question": "What famous general was once attacked by rabbits?",
    "Answer": "Napoleon",
    "A": "Napoleon",
    "B": "Julius Caesar",
    "C": "Alexander the Great",
    "D": "Genghis Khan",
    "Description": "In 1807, Napoleon had just signed the Treaty of Tilsit, which ended his war with Russia. To celebrate, he gathered his dignitaries for a rabbit hunt. Little did he know that he would become the \"hunted\". In a bizarre twist, the rabbits didn't run away. Instead, they swarmed the hunting party by the hundreds, and Napoleon was forced to retreat to his royal carriage for safety."
  },
  {
    "Question": "Which of the following empires had no written language?",
    "Answer": "Incan Empire",
    "A": "Roman Empire",
    "B": "Tang Dynasty",
    "C": "Aztec Empire",
    "D": "Incan Empire",
    "Description": "Since the Incan Empire had no written language, the main form of communication and recording in the empire were quipus, ceramics and spoken Quechua, the language the Incas imposed upon conquered peoples. The Inca's impact outlasted their empire, as the Spanish continued the use of Quechua."
  },
  {
    "Question": "Who was the first U.S. President to be impeached?",
    "Answer": "Andrew Johnson",
    "A": "Richard Nixon",
    "B": "Bill Clinton",
    "C": "Andrew Johnson",
    "D": "Herbert Hoover",
    "Description": "The Impeachment of Andrew Johnson, who became the 17th President of the United States after Abraham Lincoln's assassination, was one of the more dramatic events in the political life of the United States during Reconstruction. The first impeachment (which ultimately ended in the first acquittal) of a serving President, it was the culmination of a lengthy political battle between Johnson and the Republicans over how to best deal with the defeated Southern states following the conclusion of the American Civil War."
  },
  {
    "Question": "In what city did American colonists famously dress as Native Americans and dump an entire shipment of East India Company tea into the harbor?",
    "Answer": "Boston",
    "A": "New York",
    "B": "Boston",
    "C": "Baltimore",
    "D": "Charleston",
    "Description": "The Boston Tea Party was a political protest by the Sons of Liberty on December 16, 1773. The demonstrators, some disguised as Native Americans, in defiance of the Tea Act of May 10, 1773, destroyed an entire shipment of tea sent by the East India Company. The British government responded harshly and the episode escalated into the American Revolution."
  },
  {
    "Question": "The world's first postage stamp was introduced in what year?",
    "Answer": "1840",
    "A": "1840",
    "B": "1710",
    "C": "1906",
    "D": "1698",
    "Description": "The world's first postage stamp, the Penny Black, which featured a portrait of Queen Victoria, was introduced by Great Britain in 1840. Initially resisted by the public who didn't like the idea of pre-paying for mail delivery, the postage stamp eventually took off, and the method was quickly adopted by other countries."
  },
  {
    "Question": "When the first Burger King Restaurant opened in 1954, how much did a hamburger cost?",
    "Answer": "18 cents",
    "A": "25 cents",
    "B": "9 cents",
    "C": "75 cents",
    "D": "18 cents",
    "Description": "When David Edgerton opened the first Burger King Restaurant in 1954, he sold hamburgers for just 18 cents!"
  },
  {
    "Question": "Who was the first Prime Minister of the United Kingdom?",
    "Answer": "Robert Walpole",
    "A": "Henry Pelham",
    "B": "Robert Walpole",
    "C": "George Grenville",
    "D": "Winston Churchill",
    "Description": "Although it was not the official title during his day, Sir Robert Walpole is generally considered the first Prime Minister of the United Kingdom. He served during the reigns of George I and George II, from 1721 to 1742, making his administration the longest in British history."
  },
  {
    "Question": "What tribe of Native Americans was the first to encounter the Pilgrims?",
    "Answer": "Nauset",
    "A": "Mohican",
    "B": "Cherokee",
    "C": "Nauset",
    "D": "Pequot",
    "Description": "On December 6, 1620, the Pilgrims encountered their first Native Americans -- hostile members of the Nauset tribe. The Nauset would later become the colonists' greatest allies. Most were Christianized and aided the colonists as scouts and warriors against the other tribes. Although no longer distinct as a tribe, most of the Mashpee Wampanoag band are descended from Nauset people."
  },
  {
    "Question": "How many passengers were aboard the Mayflower when it set sail for the New World in 1620?",
    "Answer": "102",
    "A": "102",
    "B": "94",
    "C": "134",
    "D": "67",
    "Description": "There were 102 passengers aboard the Mayflower, and the crew is estimated to have been about 30. After the first winter, there were only 53 passengers, just over half, still alive."
  },
  {
    "Question": "What war lasted approximately 38 minutes?",
    "Answer": "Anglo-Zanzibar War",
    "A": "Falklands war",
    "B": "Serbo-Bulgarian war",
    "C": "Anglo-Zanzibar War",
    "D": "War of 1812",
    "Description": "The Anglo-Zanzibar War was a military conflict fought between the United Kingdom and the Zanzibar Sultanate on August 27, 1896. The conflict lasted approximately 38 minutes, making it the shortest war in history."
  },
  {
    "Question": "Who invented Arabic numerals?",
    "Answer": "Indians",
    "A": "Romans",
    "B": "Indians",
    "C": "Arabs",
    "D": "Greeks",
    "Description": "Arabic numerals originated in India in the 6th or 7th century and were introduced to Europe through Arab mathematicians around the 12th century."
  },
  {
    "Question": "Who was the first wife of King Henry VIII?",
    "Answer": "Catherine of Aragon",
    "A": "Catherine Howard",
    "B": "Catherine Parr",
    "C": "Anne Boleyn",
    "D": "Catherine of Aragon",
    "Description": "As the first wife of King Henry VIII, Catherine of Aragon was the Queen of England from June 1509 until May 1533 when the marriage was declared invalid and Henry married Anne Boleyn."
  },
  {
    "Question": "In which ocean was the Battle of Midway fought?",
    "Answer": "Pacific",
    "A": "Atlantic",
    "B": "Indian",
    "C": "Pacific",
    "D": "Southern",
    "Description": "The Battle of Midway was a decisive naval battle in the Pacific Theater of World War II. The United States Navy defeated an attacking fleet of the Imperial Japanese Navy in what military historian John Keegan has called \"the most stunning and decisive blow in the history of naval warfare."
  },
  {
    "Question": "What did ancient Egyptians use as pillows?",
    "Answer": "Stones",
    "A": "Sand",
    "B": "Stones",
    "C": "Bundles of wheat",
    "D": "Bags of water",
    "Description": "Ancient Egyptian pillows were wooden or stone headrests."
  },
  {
    "Question": "What year did Christopher Columbus set sail for the New World under the sponsorship of King Ferdinand and Queen Isabella of Spain?",
    "Answer": "1492",
    "A": "1502",
    "B": "1467",
    "C": "1477",
    "D": "1492",
    "Description": "In 1492, Columbus sailed out of Palos de la Frontera on the Santa Maria. The two accompanying ships were named the Nina and the Pinta."
  },
  {
    "Question": "Who did Spartacus fight against in the Third Servile War?",
    "Answer": "Romans",
    "A": "Romans",
    "B": "Persians",
    "C": "Greeks",
    "D": "Phoenicians",
    "Description": "Spartacus was a Thracian gladiator who, along with the Gauls Crixus, Oenomaus, Castus and Gannicus, was one of the escaped slave leaders in the Third Servile War, a major slave uprising against the Roman Republic."
  },
  {
    "Question": "What international body was established in 1945, immediately following World War II?",
    "Answer": "United Nations",
    "A": "World Bank",
    "B": "United Nations",
    "C": "League of Nations",
    "D": "NATO",
    "Description": "A replacement for the ineffective League of Nations, the United Nations was established after World War II in order to prevent another such conflict. At its founding, the UN had 51 member states."
  },
  {
    "Question": "Which Soviet satellite was the first to be launched into space in 1957?",
    "Answer": "Sputnik",
    "A": "Sputnik",
    "B": "Mir",
    "C": "Vostok",
    "D": "Venera",
    "Description": "On October 4, 1957, the Soviet Union launched Sputnik 1 which became the first artificial Earth satellite. This surprise success triggered the Space Race, a part of the larger Cold War."
  },
  {
    "Question": "What war was triggered by the shooting of a pig?",
    "Answer": "Pig war",
    "A": "Battle of the ten kings",
    "B": "Kish-Elam war",
    "C": "Moldovan-Transdniestrian war",
    "D": "Pig war",
    "Description": "The Pig War, so called because it was triggered by the shooting of a pig, is also called the Pig Episode, the Pig and Potato War, the San Juan Boundary Dispute or the Northwestern Boundary Dispute. The pig was the only \"casualty\" of the war, making the conflict essentially bloodless."
  },
  {
    "Question": "Which dictator composed six operas?",
    "Answer": "Kim Jong-il",
    "A": "Saddam Hussein",
    "B": "Adolf Hitler",
    "C": "Kim Jong-il",
    "D": "Mao Zedong",
    "Description": "Kim Jong-il was the supreme leader of the Democratic People's Republic of Korea (DPRK), commonly referred to as North Korea, from 1994 to 2011. During Kim's regime the country suffered from famine, partially due to economic mismanagement, and had a poor human rights record -- perhaps because he spent his time composing operas."
  },
  {
    "Question": "In 1912, what did a Paris orphanage give away as prizes when it held a raffle to raise money?",
    "Answer": "Babies",
    "A": "Babies",
    "B": "Rocks",
    "C": "Coal",
    "D": "Absinthe",
    "Description": "In 1912, a Paris orphanage held a raffle to raise money--the prizes were live babies. The proceeds of the raffle were divided among several charitable institutions. An investigation of the winners was made, of course, to determine their desirability as foster parents."
  },
  {
    "Question": "What charter did a group of English barons force King John to sign in 1215 at Runnymede?",
    "Answer": "Magna Carta",
    "A": "Code of Hammurabi",
    "B": "Bill of rights",
    "C": "Northwest Ordinance",
    "D": "Magna Carta",
    "Description": "First drafted by the Archbishop of Canterbury to make peace between King John and a group of rebel barons, the Magna Carta promised the protection of church rights, protection for the barons from illegal imprisonment, access to swift justice, and limitations on feudal payments to the Crown."
  },
  {
    "Question": "What did Princeton researchers Ernest Wever and Charles Bray do in 1929?",
    "Answer": "Turned a live cat into a working telephone",
    "A": "Invented the first computer",
    "B": "Turned a live cat into a working telephone",
    "C": "Discovered lsd",
    "D": "Built a miniture atomic bomb",
    "Description": "Wever and Bray removed the skull and most of the brain of a live cat and connected its auditory nerve to an electrode. When one researcher spoke in the cat's ear, the sound was seemingly converted, among the cat's neurons, into an electrical signal that was transmitted through the electrode and a connecting wire to a telephone in a separate room."
  },
  {
    "Question": "Who is generally considered the \"father of history\"?",
    "Answer": "Herodotus",
    "A": "Herodotus",
    "B": "Aristotle",
    "C": "Xenophone",
    "D": "Plato",
    "Description": "Herodotus of Halicarnassus (484 BC - c. 425 BC) was the first writer to make a conscious attempt to discover and explain past events. He is generally considered the \"father of history\". However, his contemporary Thucydides (c. 460 BC - c. 400 BC) is credited with having first approached history with a well-developed historical method in his work the History of the Peloponnesian War."
  },
  {
    "Question": "Who was the first European to discover New Zealand?",
    "Answer": "Abel Janszoon Tasman",
    "A": "Marco Polo",
    "B": "James Cook",
    "C": "Abel Janszoon Tasman",
    "D": "Marc-Joseph Marion du Fresne",
    "Description": "The first European explorer to discover New Zealand was Abel Janszoon Tasman on 13 December 1642. Captain James Cook, who reached New Zealand in October 1769 on the first of his three voyages, was the first European to circumnavigate and map New Zealand."
  },
  {
    "Question": "Who was the first Hawaiian king to venture off the islands?",
    "Answer": "Kamehameha II",
    "A": "Kalakaua",
    "B": "Kamehameha II",
    "C": "Lunalilo",
    "D": "Kamamalu",
    "Description": "Kamehameha II was the first Hawaiian king to venture off of the islands. In 1823, he and Queen Kamamalu made their first and only official state visit to England, where they both contracted measles and died shortly thereafter."
  },
  {
    "Question": "Which of the following happened in 1453?",
    "Answer": "The fall of Constantinople",
    "A": "The fall of Constantinople",
    "B": "The reformation began",
    "C": "The first book was printed using a printing press",
    "D": "Cortes began his conquest of South America",
    "Description": "The fall of Constantinople followed a 53-day siege that had begun on 6 April 1453. Almost 500 years of Turkish domination of the Eastern Mediterranean, North Africa and the Middle East would follow."
  },
  {
    "Question": "What famous writer was born in 1564?",
    "Answer": "William Shakespeare",
    "A": "Moliere",
    "B": "Geoffrey Chaucer",
    "C": "John Milton",
    "D": "William Shakespeare",
    "Description": "William Shakespeare was born in Stratford-upon-Avon and baptized there on April 26, 1564. His actual date of birth remains unknown, but is traditionally observed on April 23."
  },
  {
    "Question": "How many British colonies formed the United States of America?",
    "Answer": "13",
    "A": "50",
    "B": "13",
    "C": "24",
    "D": "9",
    "Description": "Following a series of protests over taxes in the 1760s and 1770s, these thirteen colonies united politically and militarily in opposition to the British government and fought the American Revolutionary War (1775-1783). In July 1776, they formed a new nation called the \"United States of America\" and declared independence."
  },
  {
    "Question": "What German philosopher helped Karl Marx write The Communist Manifesto?",
    "Answer": "Friedrich Engels",
    "A": "Friedrich Nietzsche",
    "B": "Arthur Schopenhaure",
    "C": "Friedrich Engels",
    "D": "Gottfried Wilhelm Leibniz",
    "Description": "Marx collaborated with German thinker Friedrich Engels and published various works, the most well-known being the 1848 pamphlet The Communist Manifesto which summarized their theories about the nature of society and politics, that in their own words, \"The history of all hitherto existing society is the history of class struggles\"."
  },
  {
    "Question": "Who was the first Catholic pope?",
    "Answer": "St. Peter",
    "A": "St. Paul",
    "B": "St. Peter",
    "C": "St. Linus",
    "D": "St. Frances",
    "Description": "The Roman Catholic Church sees Peter as the first pope upon whom God chose to build His church, ordained by Jesus in the \"Rock of My Church\" dialogue in Matthew 16:18. It holds that he had authority (primacy) over the other apostles and maintains that sometime after the recorded events of the book of Acts, the Apostle Peter became the first bishop of Rome, and that the Roman bishop was accepted by the early church as the central authority among all of the churches."
  },
  {
    "Question": "Marie Antoinette was married to which King of France?",
    "Answer": "Louis XVI",
    "A": "Louis XIV",
    "B": "Louis XVII",
    "C": "Louis XVI",
    "D": "Louis XIII",
    "Description": "On 10 May 1774, when her husband ascended the throne as Louis XVI, Marie Antoinette became Queen of France."
  },
  {
    "Question": "Which of the following was a temple on the Athenian Acropolis dedicated to the goddess Athena?",
    "Answer": "Parthenon",
    "A": "Parthenon",
    "B": "Angkor wat",
    "C": "Pantheon",
    "D": "Paestum",
    "Description": "The most renowned of Greek temples and one of the most influential buildings in the history of world architecture, the Parthenon contained a colossal statue of Athena, whom the people of Athens considered their patron."
  },
  {
    "Question": "In which caste would you most likely find a Hindu priest?",
    "Answer": "Brahmin",
    "A": "Shudras",
    "B": "Vaishyas",
    "C": "Kshatriyas",
    "D": "Brahmin",
    "Description": "Traditionally, priests have come from the Brahmin varna, although in modern times, archakas have been recruited from various communities with lesser regard to caste."
  },
  {
    "Question": "How many \"enemies of the revolution\" were officially executed during the Reign of Terror?",
    "Answer": "16594",
    "A": "9785",
    "B": "16594",
    "C": "14352",
    "D": "6790",
    "Description": "16,594 people were officially executed during the terror, with the ironic inclusion of the instigator of the killings, Robespierre himself."
  },
  {
    "Question": "What was the name of the military nobility of medieval and early-modern Japan?",
    "Answer": "Samurai",
    "A": "Samurai",
    "B": "Shogun",
    "C": "Kamikaze",
    "D": "Kazoku",
    "Description": "The samurai were usually associated with a clan and their lord, were trained as officers in military tactics and grand strategy, and they followed a set of rules that later came to be known as the bushidō. Their teachings can still be found today in modern Japanese martial arts."
  },
  {
    "Question": "For what crime was Margaret Sanger jailed in 1917?",
    "Answer": "Establishing the first birth control clinic",
    "A": "Voting",
    "B": "Tax evasion",
    "C": "Establishing the first birth control clinic",
    "D": "Giving a speech on women's rights",
    "Description": "In 1917, Sanger went to jail for distributing an early version of the diaphragm from a makeshift clinic in a tenement storefront in Brooklyn. Her conviction, when appealed, won an interpretation of New York law that allowed doctors -- though not nurses, as she intended -- to prescribe contraception for medical purposes. Under those constraints, she built the modern family planning movement."
  },
  {
    "Question": "What was the Year of the Five Emperors?",
    "Answer": "193 AD",
    "A": "17 AD",
    "B": "193 AD",
    "C": "39 BC",
    "D": "4 BC",
    "Description": "The Year of the Five Emperors refers to the year 193 AD, in which there were five claimants for the title of Roman Emperor: Pertinax, Didius Julianus, Pescennius Niger, Clodius Albinus and Septimius Severus. Out of this chaos, the Severan dynasty was born."
  },
  {
    "Question": "What famous criminal started a soup kitchen?",
    "Answer": "Al Capone",
    "A": "Al Capone",
    "B": "Adolf Eichmann",
    "C": "Jesse James",
    "D": "Charles Manson",
    "Description": "In 1931, the Chicago Tribune proclaimed that \"120,000 meals are served by Capone Free Soup Kitchen,\" making Al Capone out to be a \"Robin Hood\". Many of those served by Capone said that he was doing more for the poor than the government."
  },
  {
    "Question": "What did ancient Romans use as mouthwash?",
    "Answer": "Human Urine",
    "A": "Tortoise blood",
    "B": "Human Urine",
    "C": "Vinegar",
    "D": "Cold water",
    "Description": "The Romans used human urine to purge bacteria from the mouth. First-century Roman physicians maintained that brushing with urine whitened teeth and fixed them more firmly in the sockets. Upper-class Roman women paid dearly for bottled Portuguese urine, the most highly prized, since it was alleged to be the strongest on the Continent."
  },
  {
    "Question": "Which pope wrote an erotic novel?",
    "Answer": "Pius II",
    "A": "Inncoent IX",
    "B": "Sixtus IV",
    "C": "Pius II",
    "D": "Urban VII",
    "Description": "The Tale of Two Lovers was one of the bestselling books of the fifteenth century, even before its author, Aeneas Sylvius Piccolomini, became Pope Pius II."
  },
  {
    "Question": "Who did the Austrian army attack in the Battle of Karánsebes?",
    "Answer": "Itself",
    "A": "Germans",
    "B": "French",
    "C": "Ottomans",
    "D": "Itself",
    "Description": "The Battle of Karánsebes was a friendly fire incident during the Austro-Turkish War of 1787-1791 that began as an argument over schnapps, but escalated by a series of mishaps into a great confusion in which Austrian troops fired at every shadow, thinking the Ottomans were everywhere, but in reality shooting fellow Austrian soldiers. Two days later, the Ottoman army arrived, discovered 10,000 dead and wounded soldiers and easily took Karánsebes."
  },
  {
    "Question": "What happened on January 28, 1986?",
    "Answer": "Space shuttle Challenger exploded",
    "A": "Space shuttle Challenger exploded",
    "B": "First woman was appointed to the U.S supreme court",
    "C": "The Persian Gulf war began",
    "D": "A hole in the ozone layer was discovered",
    "Description": "Space shuttle Challenger launched and landed nine times before breaking apart 73 seconds into its tenth mission, STS-51-L, on January 28, 1986, resulting in the death of all seven crew members, including civilian school teacher Christa McAuliffe."
  },
  {
    "Question": "Who was the first woman appointed to the U.S. Supreme Court?",
    "Answer": "Sandra Day O'Connor",
    "A": "Elena Kagan",
    "B": "Ruth Bader Ginsburg",
    "C": "Sandra Day O'Connor",
    "D": "Sonia Sotomayor",
    "Description": "On August 19, 1981, Ronald Reagan -- who had pledged during his 1980 presidential campaign to appoint the first woman to the nation's highest court -- announced he would nominate Sandra Day O'Connor. She received unanimous Senate approval and served for 24 years."
  },
  {
    "Question": "When did the Great Depression begin?",
    "Answer": "24.Oct.29",
    "A": "11.Nov.18",
    "B": "15.Dec.24",
    "C": "24.Oct.29",
    "D": "18.Sep.31",
    "Description": "October 24, 1929, also known as Black Thursday, was the beginning of the most devastating stock market crash in the history of the United States. This event was the beginning of the Great Depression, which lasted for ten years."
  },
  {
    "Question": "What year was the first Internet domain registered?",
    "Answer": "1985",
    "A": "1997",
    "B": "1985",
    "C": "1979",
    "D": "1991",
    "Description": "The first domain name ever registered was Symbolics.com. It was registered March 15, 1985, to Symbolics Inc., a computer systems company in Cambridge, Mass."
  },
  {
    "Question": "What was discovered in 1985?",
    "Answer": "A hole in the ozone layer",
    "A": "Aids",
    "B": "Rings of Neptune",
    "C": "Water on Mars",
    "D": "A hole in the ozone layer",
    "Description": "The discovery of the Antarctic \"ozone hole\" by British Antarctic Survey scientists Farman, Gardiner and Shanklin (first reported in a paper in Nature in May 1985) came as a shock to the scientific community, because the observed decline in polar ozone was far larger than anyone had anticipated."
  },
  {
    "Question": "Who was Germany's first woman Chancellor?",
    "Answer": "Angela Merkel",
    "A": "Beatrix von Storch",
    "B": "Maria Baum",
    "C": "Angela Merkel",
    "D": "Janet Yellen",
    "Description": "Following the 2005 federal election, Angela Merkel was appointed Germany's first woman Chancellor at the head of a grand coalition consisting of the Christian Democratic Union (CDU), its Bavarian sister party, the Christian Social Union (CSU), and the Social Democratic Party of Germany (SPD). In December 2015, Merkel was named as Time magazine's Person of the Year, with the magazine's cover declaring her to be the \"Chancellor of the Free World."
  },
  {
    "Question": "The sinking of what ship in 1915 eventually led to the United States entering World War I?",
    "Answer": "Lusitania",
    "A": "Titanic",
    "B": "Lusitania",
    "C": "Bismarck",
    "D": "Monitor",
    "Description": "RMS Lusitania was a British ocean liner that was sunk by a German submarine in World War I. The sinking caused a storm of protest in the United States as 128 American citizens were among the dead. It helped shift public opinion in the United States against Germany and was a factor in the United States' declaration of war nearly two years later."
  },
  {
    "Question": "Who was emperor of Japan during World War II?",
    "Answer": "Hirohito",
    "A": "Mutsuhio",
    "B": "Yoshihito",
    "C": "Akihito",
    "D": "Hirohito",
    "Description": "Hirohito, emperor of Japan from 1926 until his death in 1989, was the longest-reigning monarch in Japanese history."
  },
  {
    "Question": "What German state preceded Nazi Germany?",
    "Answer": "Weimar Republic",
    "A": "Württemberg Republic",
    "B": "Weimar Republic",
    "C": "German Empire",
    "D": "German Confederation",
    "Description": "The Weimar Republic is an unofficial designation for the German state between 1919 and 1933. It came to an abrupt end on the morning of 30 January 1933 when Hitler was sworn in as Chancellor and immediately began arresting his political opponents."
  },
  {
    "Question": "What U. S. President proposed the \"New Deal\"?",
    "Answer": "Franklin D. Roosevelt",
    "A": "John F. Kennedy",
    "B": "Dwight Eisenhower",
    "C": "Franklin D. Roosevelt",
    "D": "Harry Truman",
    "Description": "In response to the Great Depression, U.S. President Franklin D. Roosevelt proposed the New Deal, a series of socially liberal programs enacted in the United States between 1933 and 1938, and focused on what historians refer to as the \"3 Rs\": Relief for the unemployed and poor, Recovery of the economy to normal levels, and Reform of the financial system to prevent a repeat depression."
  },
  {
    "Question": "Who was the first Republican Vice President of the United States?",
    "Answer": "Hannibal Hamlin",
    "A": "Abraham Lincoln",
    "B": "Andrew Johnson",
    "C": "Schuyler Colfax",
    "D": "Hannibal Hamlin",
    "Description": "The Republican Party first came to power in the election of 1860 when it won control of both houses of Congress and Abraham Lincoln was elected president. Lincoln's vice president that year was Hannibal Hamlin who was chosen in part to bring geographic balance to the ticket and in part because, as a former Democrat, he could work to convince other anti-slavery Democrats that their future lay with the Republican Party."
  },
  {
    "Question": "During the Summer of Love, where did hippies converge?",
    "Answer": "San Francisco",
    "A": "New York",
    "B": "Chicago",
    "C": "Miami",
    "D": "San Francisco",
    "Description": "During the summer of 1967, as many as 100,000 young people from around the world flocked to San Francisco's Haight-Ashbury district, Berkeley and other San Francisco Bay Area cities to join in a popularized version of the hippie experience--a melting pot of music, psychedelic drugs, sexual freedom, creative expression, and politics. The Summer of Love, as it came to be called, became a defining moment of the 1960s"
  },
  {
    "Question": "Whose death triggered a power struggle between Leon Trotsky and Joseph Stalin in 1924?",
    "Answer": "Vladimir Lenin",
    "A": "Vladimir Lenin",
    "B": "Tsar Nicholas II",
    "C": "Grigori Rasputin",
    "D": "Leo Tolstoy",
    "Description": "When Vladimir Lenin died at his home on 21 January 1924, a struggle for power developed between Stalin, the secretary of the Communist Party, and Trotsky, the Commissar for War. Stalin, a master of political trickery, used his position as secretary to put his supporters on the Central Committee of the party. He even told Trotsky the wrong date for Lenin's funeral, so Trotsky turned up a day late. And so it was Stalin who became party leader in 1924. Trotsky was dismissed, then exiled and murdered in 1940."
  },
  {
    "Question": "The Nazi invasion of what country triggered World War II in Europe?",
    "Answer": "Poland",
    "A": "Austria",
    "B": "Poland",
    "C": "France",
    "D": "Belgium",
    "Description": "On September 1, 1939, the Germans invaded Poland which led Britain and France to declare war on Hitler's Nazi state in retaliation."
  },
  {
    "Question": "The Treaty of Versailles followed which war?",
    "Answer": "World War I",
    "A": "World War II",
    "B": "The Vietnam war",
    "C": "World War I",
    "D": "The Korean war",
    "Description": "Signed on June 28, 1919, exactly five years after the assassination of Archduke Franz Ferdinand, the Treaty of Versailles followed the Versailles Peace Conference and officially ended World War I."
  },
  {
    "Question": "Who replaced Nikita Khrushchev as First Secretary of the Communist Party of the Soviet Union?",
    "Answer": "Leonid Brezhnev",
    "A": "Yuri Andropov",
    "B": "Nikolai Bulganin",
    "C": "Konstantin Chernenko",
    "D": "Leonid Brezhnev",
    "Description": "Leonid Brezhnev presided over the country from 1964 until his death in 1982. His eighteen-year term as General Secretary was second only to that of Joseph Stalin in duration."
  },
  {
    "Question": "What was the first major war campaign fought entirely by air forces?",
    "Answer": "Battle of London",
    "A": "Battle of Kursk",
    "B": "Battle of London",
    "C": "Operation Mole Cricket 19",
    "D": "Operation Linebacker",
    "Description": "The Battle of Britain, in which the Royal Air Force defended the United Kingdom against attacks from the German Air Force (Luftwaffe), was the first entirely aerial military campaign, as well as the first significant defeat for the Axis powers during World War II."
  },
  {
    "Question": "What Greek general is responsible for the project that generated most of the surviving structures on the Acropolis, including the Parthenon?",
    "Answer": "Pericles",
    "A": "Leonidas",
    "B": "Alcibiades",
    "C": "Xenophon",
    "D": "Pericles",
    "Description": "Pericles promoted the arts and literature, and it is principally through his efforts that Athens holds the reputation of being the educational and cultural center of the ancient Greek world."
  },
  {
    "Question": "What series of laws passed by the British Parliament were meant to punish Massachusetts colonists after the Boston Tea Party?",
    "Answer": "Intolerable acts",
    "A": "Intolerable acts",
    "B": "Subversive acts",
    "C": "Vindictive acts",
    "D": "Punitive acts",
    "Description": "The Intolerable Acts were the American Patriots' term for a series of punitive laws passed by the British Parliament in 1774 after the Boston Tea Party and meant to punish the Massachusetts colonists for their defiance. The British hoped these punitive measures would reverse the trend of colonial resistance to parliamentary authority, but tensions soon escalated, and the American Revolution broke out in April 1775."
  },
  {
    "Question": "What military commander was undefeated?",
    "Answer": "Alexander the Great",
    "A": "Napoleon Bonaparte",
    "B": "Julius Caesar",
    "C": "Alexander the Great",
    "D": "William the Conqueror",
    "Description": "Alexander the Great spent most of his ruling years on an unprecedented military campaign through Asia and northeast Africa, and by the age of thirty he had created one of the largest empires of the ancient world, stretching from Greece to northwestern India. He was undefeated in battle and is widely considered one of history's most successful military commanders."
  },
  {
    "Question": "Who was the first American casualty in the American Revolutionary War?",
    "Answer": "Crispus Attucks",
    "A": "John J. Williams",
    "B": "Crispus Attucks",
    "C": "John Bacon",
    "D": "Daniel Hough",
    "Description": "Crispus Attucks was the first person killed in the Boston massacre and is widely considered to be the first American casualty in the American Revolutionary War. Of Wampanoag and African descent, he became an icon of the anti-slavery movement in the 18th century and was held up as a Native American who played a heroic role in the history of the United States."
  },
  {
    "Question": "Cleopatra represented herself as the reincarnation of what Egyptian goddess?",
    "Answer": "Isis",
    "A": "Ra",
    "B": "Bastet",
    "C": "Osiris",
    "D": "Isis",
    "Description": "Cleopatra, the last active pharaoh of Ptolemaic Egypt, represented herself as the reincarnation of the Egyptian goddess Isis who was revered as the ideal mother and wife as well as the patroness of nature and magic."
  },
  {
    "Question": "What was the most popular drink in colonial America?",
    "Answer": "Tea",
    "A": "Tea",
    "B": "Whiskey",
    "C": "Beer",
    "D": "Coffee",
    "Description": "Practically everyone in colonial America drank tea, which explains why there was such an uproar when the British levied a tax on their favorite beverage."
  },
  {
    "Question": "Where was U.S. President John F. Kennedy assassinated?",
    "Answer": "Dallas",
    "A": "Austin",
    "B": "Houston",
    "C": "Dallas",
    "D": "San Antonio",
    "Description": "JFK was assassinated while driving through Dallas, Texas, in November 1963."
  },
  {
    "Question": "What Mesoamerican civilization was known for its hieroglyphic script?",
    "Answer": "Maya civilization",
    "A": "Maya civilization",
    "B": "Olmec civilization",
    "C": "Aztec civilization",
    "D": "Inca civilization",
    "Description": "The Maya civilization was noted for its hieroglyphic script--the only known fully developed writing system of the pre-Columbian Americas--as well as for its art, architecture, mathematics, calendar, and astronomical system."
  },
  {
    "Question": "The Great Leap Forward in China was primarily designed to do which of the following?",
    "Answer": "Achieve rapid industrialization",
    "A": "Promote capitalism",
    "B": "Oust the imperial government",
    "C": "Achieve rapid industrialization",
    "D": "Establish military dominance",
    "Description": "The Great Leap Forward was an economic and social campaign by the Communist Party of China from 1958 to 1962. The campaign was led by Chairman Mao Zedong and aimed to transform the country from an agrarian economy into a socialist society through rapid industrialization. However, it is widely considered to have caused the Great Chinese Famine."
  },
  {
    "Question": "Where was Adolf Hitler born?",
    "Answer": "Austria",
    "A": "Poland",
    "B": "Austria",
    "C": "Germany",
    "D": "Hungary",
    "Description": "Hitler was born in Braunau am Inn, a town in Austria-Hungary (present-day Austria), close to the border with the German Empire."
  },
  {
    "Question": "Differences between which two religions contributed to violent conflicts during the Indian struggle for independence in 1947?",
    "Answer": "Hinduism and Islam",
    "A": "Hinduism and Christianity",
    "B": "Islam and Christianity",
    "C": "Hinduism and Islam",
    "D": "Buddhism and Hinduism",
    "Description": "Although the Indian National Congress of Mohandas Gandhi and Jawaharlal Nehru strongly opposed sectarian divisions within the independence movement, many Indian Muslims believed the Indian National Congress was dominated by Hindu political interests and that, should India remain unified after the British withdrawal, it would inevitably become a Hindu state. As a result of these fears, the Muslim League of Muhammad Ali Jinnah began supporting the \"Two Nation Theory\" which advocated for the creation of a separate Pakistani state."
  },
  {
    "Question": "What was the goal of the Marshall Plan?",
    "Answer": "All of the above",
    "A": "Prevent the spread of communism",
    "B": "Rebuild war-devastated regions",
    "C": "Remove trade barriers",
    "D": "All of the above",
    "Description": "The Marshall Plan (officially the European Recovery Program) was an American initiative to aid Western Europe after World War II. The United States gave over $12 billion in economic support with the following goals in mind: to rebuild war-devastated regions, remove trade barriers, modernize industry, and prevent the spread of communism."
  },
  {
    "Question": "Social Darwinists believed that ______.",
    "Answer": "Human societies progress through competition",
    "A": "Human societies progress through cooperation",
    "B": "Human societies progress through competition",
    "C": "God predetermines the faith of a society",
    "D": "Competition and cooperation are equally important in a society",
    "Description": "Social Darwinists tried to apply Charles Darwin's biological concepts of natural selection and survival of the fittest to human society, arguing that human societies progress through competition, since the strong survive and the weak perish"
  },
  {
    "Question": "What was the purpose of the British government's 1765 Stamp Act?",
    "Answer": "To raise revenue for the crown",
    "A": "To make the customs service more efficient",
    "B": "To honor deceased artists",
    "C": "To raise revenue for the crown",
    "D": "To punish rebellious colonists",
    "Description": "Colonial tax rates had until this time been lower than those in Great Britain, so Prime Minister George Grenville sought the passage of the Stamp Act in order to spread taxation more evenly and generate revenue for the British government (that is, for the crown). This law prompted widespread protests in the North American colonies."
  },
  {
    "Question": "What year did the California Gold Rush start?",
    "Answer": "1848",
    "A": "1848",
    "B": "1867",
    "C": "1901",
    "D": "1792",
    "Description": "The California Gold Rush began on January 24, 1848, when gold was found by James W. Marshall at Sutter's Mill in Coloma, California. The news brought some 300,000 people to California from the rest of the United States and abroad."
  },
  {
    "Question": "Who was the first First Lady to run for President of the United States?",
    "Answer": "Hillary Clinton",
    "A": "Betty Ford",
    "B": "Hillary Clinton",
    "C": "Nancy Reagan",
    "D": "Michelle Obama",
    "Description": "Hillary Clinton served as the First Lady of the United States from 1993 to 2001 and became the Democratic Party's nominee for President in 2016."
  },
  {
    "Question": "Which war was ended by the 1763 Treaty of Paris?",
    "Answer": "Seven years' war",
    "A": "Hundred years' war",
    "B": "Forty years' war",
    "C": "Seven years' war",
    "D": "Twelve years' war",
    "Description": "The signing of the treaty formally ended the Seven Years' War, also known as the French and Indian War."
  },
  {
    "Question": "Which political party was banned in Italy after World War II?",
    "Answer": "Facist party",
    "A": "Communist party",
    "B": "Facist party",
    "C": "Socialist party",
    "D": "Nazi party",
    "Description": "The National Fascist Party along with its successor, the Republican Fascist Party, are the only parties whose re-formation is banned by the Constitution of Italy."
  },
  {
    "Question": "What was the first capital of ancient Egypt?",
    "Answer": "Memphis",
    "A": "Memphis",
    "B": "Alexandria",
    "C": "Thebes",
    "D": "Cairo",
    "Description": "The first capital of ancient Egypt was Memphis, a city whose name can be roughly translated into English as \"White Walls.\" Located in Lower Egypt, just below the Nile Delta, Memphis was founded by Menes, the first king of Egypt, around 3,000 B.C. following his unification of the country. During the First Dynasty, Egypt's center of government was located in Memphis because the city united Upper and Lower Egypt. Memphis is famous for the cemetery at Saqqara. According to legend, it is also the site Osiris descended to the Underworld and became the Judge of the Dead."
  },
  {
    "Question": "On what island did ancient Greek civilization originate?",
    "Answer": "Crete",
    "A": "Samos",
    "B": "Olympia",
    "C": "Rhodes",
    "D": "Crete",
    "Description": "Ancient Greek civilization is believed to have originated on the island of Crete. It is unclear when the island was first settled, but there are archaeological remains dating as far back as 5000 B.C.. The general consensus is that the first wave of settlers came from Anatolia and Africa, followed by another wave of settlers from Asia around 2600 B.C.. This second wave brought with it highly developed artistic skills. These new settlers interbred with the previous inhabitants, and as a result Minoan culture, a precursor of Greek civilization, was born."
  },
  {
    "Question": "Who is considered the founder of the Xia Dynasty in ancient China?",
    "Answer": "Yu",
    "A": "Tang",
    "B": "Yu",
    "C": "Xiu",
    "D": "Shun",
    "Description": "Yu the Great is generally considered the founder of the Xia Dynasty in China. This dynasty -- which lasted from the 21st century B.C. to the 17th century B.C. -- included seventeen kings and over fourteen generations of rulers. Sometimes identified as one of the Three August Ones and the Five Emperors, Yu is best known for creating flood control techniques to control China's massive rivers and lakes. In fact, he was so successful at this task that the previous ruler, Shun, passed the throne to him instead of his own son."
  },
  {
    "Question": "How many of the Seven Wonders of the Ancient World still exist?",
    "Answer": "1",
    "A": "0",
    "B": "2",
    "C": "3",
    "D": "1",
    "Description": "Of the Seven Wonders of the Ancient World, only one remains: the Great Pyramid of Giza. The lost wonders include the Hanging Gardens of Babylon, the Statue of Zeus at Olympia, the Temple of Artemis at Ephesus, the Mausoleum at Halicarnassus, the Colossus of Rhodes, and the Lighthouse of Alexandria."
  },
  {
    "Question": "When did the first documented Olympic Games take place?",
    "Answer": "776 BC",
    "A": "776 BC",
    "B": "367 BC",
    "C": "456 BC",
    "D": "569 BC",
    "Description": "The first documented Olympic Games took place in 776 B.C.. Many historians, however, believe that the Games had already been established for many years at that point. According to legend, the Olympic Games were founded by Heracles, the son of Zeus. There was only one event at the 776 B.C. Olympic Games -- the stade, a race of approximately 192 meters. The winner was Coroebus, a cook from Elis, making him the first documented Olympic champion in history."
  },
  {
    "Question": "Who is credited with making the first map of the known world?",
    "Answer": "Anaximander",
    "A": "Archimedes",
    "B": "Anaximander",
    "C": "Euclid",
    "D": "Plato",
    "Description": "Anaximander, a philosopher from Miletus who lived during the first half of the 6th century B.C., is credited with making the first map of the known world around 540 B.C.. He also invented a type of sun dial."
  },
  {
    "Question": "What Roman Emperor was once captured by pirates and held for a 12,000 gold-piece ransom?",
    "Answer": "Julius Caesar",
    "A": "Nero",
    "B": "Caligula",
    "C": "Julius Caesar",
    "D": "Caesar Augustus",
    "Description": "On his way home from the siege of Miletus, Julius Caesar was captured by pirates and held hostage for about forty days. Caesar insisted that his captors double their ransom demand (he was, after all, an aristocrat) and promised to return and punish them. True to his word, Caesar returned after his release, hunted the pirates down, and had them crucified."
  },
  {
    "Question": "What incident in 1962 nearly led to a nuclear confrontation between the U.S. and Russia?",
    "Answer": "Cuban missile crisis",
    "A": "Korean war",
    "B": "Cuban missile crisis",
    "C": "Yalta conference",
    "D": "Vietnam war",
    "Description": "On October 22, 1962, the Cuban Missile Crisis began when U.S. President John F. Kennedy announced that the Soviet Union was building a secret missile base in Cuba, just 90 miles off the coast of Florida. Hoping to avoid an armed invasion of Cuba, Kennedy opted for a naval quarantine of the island and demanded that Russian Premier Nikita Khrushchev remove all weapons. In response to the blockade, Khrushchev authorized his field commanders to launch nuclear weapons if attacked by U.S. forces. The two nations remained deadlocked for seven days before Khrushchev reconsidered and gave in to Kennedy's demands."
  },
  {
    "Question": "What series of anti-government protests and uprisings spread across much of the Arab world in the early 2010s?",
    "Answer": "Arab spring",
    "A": "Arab spring",
    "B": "Arab rebellion",
    "C": "Arab awakening",
    "D": "Arab strike",
    "Description": "The Arab Spring began in response to oppressive regimes and a low standard of living, starting with protests in Tunisia."
  },
  {
    "Question": "What body of water was contaminated when the Deepwater Horizon oil rig exploded on April 20, 2010?",
    "Answer": "Gulf of Mexico",
    "A": "Persian gulf",
    "B": "Gulf of Alaska",
    "C": "Hudson bay",
    "D": "Gulf of Mexico",
    "Description": "The Deepwater Horizon oil spill, which leaked 4.9 million barrels (210 million US gal; 780,000 m3) into the Gulf of Mexico, was one of the worst environmental disasters in U.S. history."
  },
  {
    "Question": "What year did the first man walk on the Moon?",
    "Answer": "1969",
    "A": "1967",
    "B": "1969",
    "C": "1960",
    "D": "1972",
    "Description": "On July 20 (July 21 GMT), 1969, American astronaut Neil Armstrong became the first man to walk on the Moon. As he stepped onto the Moon's surface, in the Sea of Tranquility, Armstrong uttered the now-famous words: \"That's one small step for man; one giant leap for mankind."
  },
  {
    "Question": "What nation exploded its first nuclear bomb in the Rajasthan Desert in 1974?",
    "Answer": "India",
    "A": "Russia",
    "B": "Iran",
    "C": "India",
    "D": "Pakistan",
    "Description": "On May 18, 1974, India exploded its first nuclear bomb in the Rajasthan Desert near the town of Pokhran, describing the event as a \"peaceful nuclear explosion.\" According to various reports, the underground test produced a crater with a radius somewhere between 47 and 75 meters."
  },
  {
    "Question": "What year did scientists complete a map of the human genome?",
    "Answer": "2000",
    "A": "1986",
    "B": "1995",
    "C": "2000",
    "D": "2007",
    "Description": "In June of 2000, scientists at Celera Genomics announced that they had completed the first map of the human genome. This accomplishment was immediately recognized as one of the greatest achievements in scientific history. A more complete map was released in April of 2003."
  },
  {
    "Question": "June 6, 1944, is better known as what?",
    "Answer": "D-day",
    "A": "V-day",
    "B": "C-day",
    "C": "The day",
    "D": "D-day",
    "Description": "On June 6, 1944, the Invasion of Normandy began as U.S., British, and Canadian forces set out to liberate Europe from Nazi control. It was the largest air, land, and sea operation ever undertaken, involving more than 5,000 ships, 11,000 airplanes, and 150,000 soldiers. When the dust cleared, Allied Forces had suffered almost 10,000 casualties but the German lines had been breached and the defeat of Hitler was in sight. The success of D-Day was absolutely essential to Allied victory in World War II."
  },
  {
    "Question": "What toy was introduced in Australian stores in 1957 after proving to be a popular exercise tool in schools?",
    "Answer": "Hula hoop",
    "A": "Jump rope",
    "B": "Roller skates",
    "C": "Hula hoop",
    "D": "Frisbee",
    "Description": "Wham-O, a fledgling California toy manufacturer, soon took notice of the Australian Hula Hoop craze and began selling plastic hoops in the United States. Within four months, twenty-five million Hula Hoops had been sold!"
  },
  {
    "Question": "What famous painting was stolen from a Norwegian museum in 2004?",
    "Answer": "The scream",
    "A": "The last supper",
    "B": "Starry night",
    "C": "The Mona Lisa",
    "D": "The scream",
    "Description": "On August 22, 2004, two armed robbers stole \"The Scream,\" a famous painting by Edvard Munch, from the Munch Museum in Norway. They also escaped with another Munch painting entitled \"The Madonna.\" The museum estimated that the two stolen paintings were worth approximately $19 million (£10.4 million). On March 7, 2005, three more works by Munch were stolen from a hotel in Norway: a 1915 watercolor entitled \"Blue Dress\" and two lithographs including a self-portrait of the artist. Authorities did not know if the two robberies were related."
  }
]
